We are going to be discussing about this malitment in this video.
This malitment is a system utility in Windows that enables you to perform advanced storage task.
So here are some of the things this malitment is actually good for.
To set up a new drive life, for example, to initialize a new disk drive, if you want to
attend a volume into space that is not already part of a volume on the same drive, like
extending a basic volume, and three, to actually shrink a partition, we are usually
so that you can extend a neighboring partition, like shrinking a basic volume.
And, fortunately, to change the drive, let's say, our signing, you know, drive.
So to open the disk malitment on your Windows 7 or Windows 10 or Windows 11, the files
what you need to do is, you need to assign it to your device and then right click your
start menu, and there you can see we have disk malitment.
So just click on this malitment.
So here we go.
You can see what we have.
So this car has gone.
Well, let me just cancel this for now, and then expand the disk malitment.
So when you open the disk malitment for the first time, you can see, for example, here
we have a basic disk.
What is a basic disk?
With a basic disk, we can actually create until its partition.
We can use a, we can create a logical drive when we have a basic disk.
We can format and make it active.
We can extend only to add the send, continuous, on the same disk.
So when you right click, the basic disk, for example, when I right click this, you can
see a hard opportunity to convert this to a dynamic disk.
Then what is a dynamic disk?
A dynamic disk is actually built in data about the drive.
It's actually written on that volume, and you can expand to a non-configure space or
order this.
We can actually move and replace the dynamic disk.
So let's, as I mean, for example, we have a disk zero.
You can see, when you click this zero, you can see we have, for example, the EFI system
partition.
So the EFI system partition, also called the ESP is an operating system independent
partition that acts as a storage place for the EFI, both load as applications and drivers
to be launched by the EFI firmware.
So we also have the recovery partition.
The recovery partition is actually a special partition on the hard drive, which is used
to restore the system in the event of a disk failure, or you have a problem with your device.
That's actually what the recovery partition is actually meant for.
And lastly, on the disk zero, you can see we have a C drive.
So the C drives are totally very, very potent.
And in the center, I have quite a lot of contents, the Windows boot operating system.
And this actually contains the primary partition of this device.